"Motivation"
MOTIVAÇÃO
I'm totally lacking motivation.
Estou sem nenhuma motivação.
What are you talking about? We're high schoolers now.
Do que está falando?
It's a brand new semester.
Acabamos de começar.
You'll find plenty of motivation if you just stick to it.
Vai encontrar motivação se aguentar firme.
I can't even get motivated to find motivation.
Não tenho motivação para encontrar motivação.
How am I supposed to get motivated to do that?
Como ficar motivada para fazer isso?
Motivation to find motivation, hmm...
Motivação para ter motivação.
You've just gotta do it!
FAÇA PARTE DO CLUBE DE IGOTEBOL!
All right!
Está bem!
It must be nice being a complete idiot.
Deve ser legal ser uma idiota.
Hakase! Isn't it about time you woke up?
LABORATÓRIO DA SHINONOME
"My Ordinary Life 1"
MINHA VIDA COTIDIANA PARTE 1
There we go...
Aqui está...
Good morning.
Bom dia.
What are you doing?
O que está fazendo?
Today's breakfast is grilled fish.
O café de hoje é peixe grelhado.
What? But I want omurice...
O quê? Mas eu quero omelete.
You just had some yesterday.
Você comeu isso ontem.
Fish is very nutritious, you know!
Peixe é muito nutritivo, sabia?
If you don't have a balanced diet, you'll never grow--
Se não tiver uma dieta balanceada, nunca vai crescer.
Um! That's supposed to be our breakfast!
Esse era o nosso café da manhã!
Th-This isn't a robotic part or anything!
Isso não é uma peça robótica nem nada!
Um, you see...
Entende...
He ran away.
Ele foi embora.
Wait!
Espere!
Goodbye.
Tchau.
I wonder...
Fico pensando que...
Does that cat need it more than we do?
talvez ele precise mais do que nós.
We're gonna crash!
Vamos bater!
I realized just this very moment
Eu percebi neste exato momento
I think I might have fallen in love
Que acho que posso ter me apaixonado
24 hours a day of you you you
24 horas por dia de você
I can't get you out of my head!
Eu não consigo tirar você Da minha cabeça!
Something (something) feels different now
Algo (Algo) parece diferente agora
With you (together) it's awkward conversation
Com você (Juntos) é uma conversa estranha
Is it (mutual love) no it's one-sided love
É (Amor mútuo) Não, é amor unilateral
Uh-oh I think our eyes just met!
Acho que nossos olhos Acabaram de se encontrar!
What is this anxious nervous feeling?
O que é essa sensação De ansiedade e nervosismo?
My train of thought is tangled with confusion...
Minha linha de pensamento Está emaranhada e confusa
This kind of thing is a first for me
É uma primeira vez para mim
Could it be a fever and I'm sick?
Talvez seja febre e estou doente
With a sudden twist it's awakened love
Com uma reviravolta repentina O amor é despertado
There's a fire in my cheeks and my face is all red
Minhas bochechas pegam fogo E meu rosto está todo vermelho
Th-Th-This can't be real, my hands are trembling
Isso não pode ser real Minhas mãos estão tremendo
Is this what people mean when they talk about "love"?
É isso que as pessoas querem dizer Quando falam sobre "amor"?
I-I-I'm stuttering non-stop talking to you
Estou gaguejando sem parar Quando falo com você
Awkward silence and then mumble-mumble-mo
Silêncio constrangedor E depois fico enrolado
I wanna (I wanna) know how you feel about me
Eu quero (Eu quero) Saber o que você sente por mim
O-O-O-One one-sided love
Amor unilateral
Sparkle-sparkle dazzling I DO fall in love!
Cintilante, deslumbrante Eu me apaixono
It's like I'm flying through the sky
É como se eu estivesse voando pelo céu
O-O-O-One one-sided love
Amor unilateral
"Wooden doll"
BONECA DE MADEIRA
"Red cow"
VACA VERMELHA
"Salmon"
SALMÃO
Mio! Selamat pagi! [Malay for "Good Morning."]
Mio! Selamat pagi!
Oh, Yuuko. Good morning.
Yuuko. Bom dia.
What should I do? I forgot to put on my student badge.
Esqueci a minha carteirinha de estudante.
Huh? Did she just ignore my selamat pagi?
Ela ignorou o meu "selamat pagi"?
I hope some upperclassman doesn't call me out.
Espero que nenhum representante reclame.
If that happens, just tell them you're a 3rd year student or something.
Se reclamarem, diz que você é estudante do terceiro ano.
That's not gonna solve anything.
Não vai adiantar nada.
What? Was that thunder? But it's clear out...
Isso foi trovão? Mas o céu está limpo.
It might start pouring from the sky!
Deve começar a chover.
What if we get rained on? Or it hails?
E se a gente se molhar? É granizo?
It's raining wooden dolls.
Está chovendo bonecas.
A-Are you all right, Yuuko?!
Você está bem, Yuuko?
A wooden doll, of all things...
Justo uma boneca de madeira.
That's weird. I wonder where it came from?
Que estranho! De onde veio?
How am I supposed to know?
Como vou saber?
It's gotta be super rare to be hit by a wooden doll from the sky.
Deve ser raro ser atingida por uma boneca de madeira caindo do céu.
It never happens to people, does it?
Não deve acontecer sempre, né?
It really doesn't.
Não acontece mesmo.
So maybe I'm extremely lucky!
Então devo ser muito sortuda!
I take that back...
Retiro o que disse.
Yuuko, you okay?
Yuuko, você está bem?
A red cow, of all things...
Justo uma vaca vermelha.
A red cow...
Uma vaca vermelha.
Maybe it's not that I'm lucky. Think about it like this, Mio.
Talvez não seja questão de sorte.
At least I wasn't hit by anything raw.
Pelo menos, não fui atingida por nada cru.
Like they say, it could've been worse...
Como dizem, podia ter sido pior.
Salmon!
Salmão!
Morning.
Bom dia.
"Come and join the Go+Soccer club!!!"
FAÇA PARTE DO CLUBE DE IGOTEBOL! PROCUREM A ALUNA SATOU DA TURMA 3Q.
Good morning, Mai.
Bom dia, Mai.
Selamat pagi.
Selamat pagi.
Good morning.
Bom dia.
What are you reading, Mai?
O que está lendo, Mai?
A real estate magazine.
Uma revista de imóveis.
What? Are you moving, Mai?
O quê? Vai se mudar, Mai?
Haven't decided.
Ainda não decidi.
Yet again, my selamat pagi gets no reaction.
De novo, ignoraram meu "selamat pagi".
Oh well. I think it's time to put that phrase to rest.
Bom, acho melhor não falar mais essa expressão.
Yuuko.
Yuuko.
Selamat malam. [Good Evening]
Selamat malam.
Silly Mai! It's selamat pagi!
Sua boba! O certo é selamat pagi!
What language is that?
Que língua é essa?
I-It's time to start homeroom.
Está na hora da orientação.
Um... When I got to school this morning, I found this in my shoe rack.
Quando cheguei na escola hoje,
Did any of you put it there?
Algum de vocês colocou isto lá?
U-Uh...
Olha...
If there's anyone who knows who did it, please tell me!
Se alguém souber, me avise, por favor!
Hey, Mio. I wonder who could've done that.
Mio, quem deve ter colocado aquilo lá?
It's probably just a prank.
Deve ser brincadeira.
What if it's from some student who has a crush on her?
E se for de um estudante que tem uma quedinha por ela?
Who would give their crush a Buddha statue?
Quem daria uma estátua do Buda?
Though I get the feeling of wanting to give something to the person you like.
Mas entendo querer presentear a pessoa que você gosta.
Yeah, I bet you do.
Deve entender mesmo.
Is that how you feel when you think of Sasahara?
É assim que você se sente com o Sasahara?
Y-You idiot!
Sua idiota!
Where in the world am I?
Onde estou?
I need to get home...
Preciso entrar.
Hakase is probably worried, and it's dangerous to keep the grill burning.
A Doutora deve estar preocupada, e é perigoso deixar a grelha acesa.
I can't even get down from here!
Não consigo descer daqui!
My chopsticks are gone! My slipper, too!
Meu palito sumiu!
What should I do?!
O que devo fazer?
My hand's gone!
Minha mão sumiu!
Everyone will know I'm a robot!
Todos vão saber que eu sou um robô.
Ready?
Pronto?
"Wonderful"
MARAVILHA
Thanks for the meal.
Valeu pela comida.
Hurry and eat. Fifth period is our language lab.
Anda logo. A próxima aula é de linguagem.
Huh? Do you not like sausage?
Você não gosta de salsicha?
Don't you know to save the best part of your lunch for last?
Não sabe que se deve deixar a melhor parte por último?
That way, you can say "Yum!" when you're done.
Assim, você pode gritar: "Que gostoso!" quando acabar.
Without further ado... It's chow time!
Sem mais delongas, é hora de devorar!
"My Ordinary Life 2"
MINHA VIDA COTIDIANA PARTE 2
It broke through!
- Atravessou! - Não é o fim!
It's over!
É o fim!
It's not over yet!
Ainda não é o fim!
One...
Um...
Two...
Dois...
Three...
Três...
Safe!
Salvei!
That's so out!
Salvou nada!
Sheesh, Mio! No one ever told you about the three-second rule?
Calma, Mio! Não conhece a regra dos três segundos?
You're so out it's not even funny!
Ficou muito tempo no chão!
Yum!
Que gostoso!
Yuuko's such an idiot.
A Yuuko é uma bobona.
First comes rock, then your hand delivers...
Primeiro é a pedra, depois é o papel
What's it gonna be, no cheats! Rock-paper-scissors!
O que será? Sem roubar! Pedra, papel, tesoura!
Okay!
Pronta!
Good morning, everybody.
Bom dia, pessoal.
With the coming of spring, we welcome a new school year.
Com a mudança de estação, começamos o ano letivo.
But the days will continue to stay cold for some time.
Os dias ainda serão frios por um tempo.
Though in my case, I'll feel the cold a bit more than all of you.
No meu caso, sinto mais frio do que vocês.
"My Ordinary Life 3"
MINHA VIDA COTIDIANA PARTE 3
So please be careful not to catch a cold.
Então cuidado para não se resfriarem.
That is my appeal to you as your principal.
É o pedido que faço como diretor da escola.
And if you don't listen and do as I ask...
E, se não fizerem o que eu pedi,
...I'll become the principal of a different school.
vou ser diretor de outra escola.
Mio, Mio.
Mio, Mio.
What? We'll get in trouble if we talk.
O que foi? Vamos levar bronca.
Do you think the principal knows that his jokes aren't funny?
Acha que o diretor sabe que suas piadas são sem graça?
You'd think the one saying the jokes would realize that nobody's laughing.
Ele está contando as piadas, então tinha que notar que ninguém está rindo.
What if he knows he's not funny,
Será que ele sabe que não tem graça,
but he's just trying to teach our lazy generation the importance of persistence?
mas está tentando ensinar
If that's actually true, our principal might be a mastermind!
Se isso for verdade,
Mai?!
Mai?
Mai, what?!
Mai, o que foi?
She's laughing at these terrible jokes?
Está achando graça das piadas?
Really?!
Sério?
I've never seen her laugh this hard in my life!
Nunca a vi rir tanto na minha vida.
This is my one chance!
É a minha chance!
Mai!
Mai!
Why is it...?
Por que sinto
If I try saying it now, I feel like I'll lose everything...
que se eu disser algo, vou pôr tudo em risco?
Yuuko.
Yuuko.
Sorry. Never mind.
Desculpa. Deixa pra lá.
I won't say anything until she notices...
Não direi nada
Let's just leave it where it is.
É melhor deixar pra lá mesmo.
"Squid tentacle"
TENTÁCULO DE LULA
Next is a message from the student counselor, Ms. Sakurai.
A seguir, um recado da orientadora, Srta. Sakurai.
If you please, Ms. Sakurai.
Por favor, Srta. Sakurai.
Sorry! I'm the student counselor, Ms. Sakurai!
Desculpe! Sou a orientadora, Srta. Sakurai!
Sorry... Uh, um...
Desculpe.
No! I can't let this stop me!
Tenho que aguentar firme!
I'll never become the perfect teacher at this rate!
Senão nunca vou ser uma professora perfeita!
I've got to say what needs to be said!
Tenho que falar o que precisa ser dito!
That's right!
Isso mesmo!
Lately, I've noticed goats in the school grounds.
Tenho visto cabras dentro da escola.
Please try not to bring goats to the school!
Por favor, não tragam cabras à escola!
Goats...
Cabras.
What's wrong with goats?!
Qual é o problema de cabras?
Nowhere in the school policy does it say that we can't ride a goat to school!
As regras da escola
Uh, um... Well...
Bem...
Mio? Wasn't that Sasahara?
Mio, esse não é o Sasahara?
Yeah? Really?
É?
Uh... Goats can be an exception!
Cabras podem ser uma exceção.
Denied, I say! Denied!
Recusado, digo eu!
Totally denied!
Recusadíssimo!
You're not allowed to ride goats to school!
Não pode vir de cabra até a escola!
So you say, Misato Tachibana.
Você que acha, Misato Tachibana.
Why should I be forced to hobble my way to school?
Por que eu deveria ser obrigado a andar até aqui?
As the eldest son of the Sasahara household--
Sou o filho mais velho da casa dos Sasahara.
Don't give me that Sasahara household crap!
Não me venha com essa bobagem!
You guys are just your typical farmers!
Vocês são apenas fazendeiros!
And what of it? That doesn't change the fact that I'm the eldest son.
E daí? Eu continuo sendo o filho mais velho.
Eh? So Sasahara's family are farmers?
Os Sasahara são fazendeiros?
I feel kinda lied to.
Sinto que mentiram para mim.
That white goat at the bike rack must have been Sasahara's.
Aquela cabra no bicicletário devia ser do Sasahara.
Riding majestically atop a white goat, Sasahara comes to take me away...
PROIBIÇÃO NEGADA
A happy new year.
Feliz Ano Novo.
Mio!
Mio!
Let's all stop doing this.
Vamos parar com isso.
And lastly...
Por último...
This morning, I found a Buddha statue in my shoe rack.
Encontrei uma estátua do Buda na sapateira.
I do not appreciate pranks of this nature!
Não gosto de brincadeiras desse tipo!
Excuse me. Coming through.
Com licença. Estamos passando.
A Buddha statue...
Uma estátua do Buda.
Mai! Don't just stop out of nowhere!
Mai, não pare de repente!
There it is.
Aqui está ele.
It's déjà vu.
É déjà vu.
Which one of you did this?
Quem de vocês fez isso?
I won't be angry, so raise your hand if you did.
Não vou dar bronca. Levante a mão.
This morning assembly will not end until someone comes forward.
A reunião só vai terminar quando o culpado aparecer.
Who did it?
- Quem fez isso? - Diz logo.
Well, I overheard that it was your birthday, Ms. Sakurai.
Soube que era o seu aniversário, Srta. Sakurai.
Ah, I see...
Entendi.
I guess a Buddha statue wasn't the greatest idea.
A estátua do Buda não foi uma boa ideia.
One thought it good for a present.
ELE ACHOU QUE ERA UM BOM PRESENTE.
A Buddha statue gift is not so pleasant.
NÃO É UM PRESENTE AGRADÁVEL - DIRETOR.
--Principal.
Diretor.
That concludes the morning assembly.
Está encerrada a reunião.
We will all miss you dearly, Principal.
Vamos sentir saudades, diretor.
Vice Principal?!
Vice-diretor?
"Fire alarm." "Push."
ALARME DE INCÊNDIO. APERTE O BOTÃO EXTINTOR DE INCÊNDIO
Doesn't seeing this fire alarm button make you wanna push it?
Você não tem vontade de apertar o botão do alarme de incêndio?
It does.
Tenho.
Why don't you push it? When I pressed it before, nothing happened at all.
Por que você não aperta? Quando apertei, não aconteceu nada.
What? Really?
O quê? Sério?
A fire?!
- Incêndio? - De verdade?
What do we do? Run?
Devemos correr?
Everyone, hurry! Out to the yard!
Rápido, gente! Para o pátio!
What are you doing?! Quit pushing me!
Pare de me empurrar!
You pushed me first!
Me empurrou antes.
You kidding?! You're really ticking me off!
Está de brincadeira? Você está me irritando!
Quit it! People could die here!
Parem com isso! Alguém pode morrer aqui!
Let's get outta here! You guys can fight later!
Vamos! Podem brigar mais tarde!
Um...
Com licença.
Excuse me? What does "insensitive" mean?
O que significa "insensível"?
What does it mean to be insensitive?
O que significa ser insensível?
Excuse me? Please explain being insensitive to me!
Por favor, me explique o que é ser insensível!
Somebody help!
Alguém me ajuda!
Hey!
- Oi! - Capitão!
Can you tell me what's insensitive?
Sabe o que é "insensível"?
You are.
Você.
"Rules and Essentials" Koujirou Sasahara of Class 2-P.
REGRAS E FUNDAMENTOS
Come to the faculty room immediately.
venha à Diretoria imediatamente.
True, it may not be against the school policy...
É verdade. Não é proibido.
But riding a goat, really?
Mas por que andar de cabra?
You can't put an end to this?
Não pode parar com isso?
You can always ride a bike. Just not a goat.
Você pode andar de bicicleta, mas não uma cabra.
Mister.
- Professor. - Meu nome é Tomioka.
Tomioka.
Tomioka.
Don't forget the Mr.
"Professor".
Mr.
Professor.
Could you not call him a goat, but Kojiro Sasahara?
Pode chamá-lo de Kojiro Sasahara, em vez de cabra?
I'll stick with goat for now.
Vou continuar chamando assim.
"Shinonome Lab"
LABORATÓRIO DA SHINONOME
"My Ordinary Life 4"
MINHA VIDA COTIDIANA PARTE 4
My name is Nano Shinonome.
Meu nome é Nano Shinonome.
I'm a robot that lives with Hakase who made me.
Sou um robô que mora com a Doutora. Foi ela quem me fez.
Hakase always stays inside the house doing some sort of research.
A Doutora está sempre dentro de casa, pesquisando algo.
I'm passing the days helping her all that I can.
Eu aproveito para ajudá-la da forma que posso.
Hakase! I brought some warm milk for y--
Doutora! Eu trouxe leite morno...
I don't really have any special features, but I apparently have nerves.
Não tenho funções especiais, mas, aparentemente, tenho nervos.
Nano? What's wrong?
Nano, o que foi?
Hakase! My pinky toe! My pinky toe!
Doutora! Meu dedinho! Meu dedinho!
It should feel a little better now...
Agora deve melhorar.
I don't really have any special features, but apparently my pinky toe comes off.
Não tenho funções especiais, mas, aparentemente, meu dedinho sai.
Hakase? What is this key for?
Doutora, para que serve essa chave?
I've never wound it up for you?
Nunca dei corda em você?
Yeah, but it does spin sometimes.
Deu, mas ela gira, às vezes.
So you twist it like this...
É só girar assim...
What's happening?!
O que é isso?
I take it back. I have all sorts of special features.
TUBARÃO
See? It's cool isn't it?
Viu? Não é legal?
Is that the only reason for the key on my back?
Esse é o propósito
Yup.
É.
Is that the only reason for the key on my back?!
É o único propósito dessa chave nas minhas costas?
Yup!
É!
Take it off!
- Tire-a! - Não!
Because it's so cute.
Ela é bonitinha.
For real, take it off!
É sério, tire-a!
But it's so cute...
Mas é bonitinha.
I just want to be more normal.
Quero apenas ser normal.
Sit in a chair like normal people...
Sentar na cadeira como pessoas normais.
Be able to roll over in bed...
Poder rolar na cama.
At this rate, I'll never be able to go to school.
Assim, nunca vou poder ir à escola.
It would have been better if you never made me a humanoid robot.
Teria sido melhor se eu não fosse um robô humanóide.
Nano...
Nano.
I-I'm just kidding, okay?
É brincadeira, está bem?
I'm kidding! You can stop crying now, Hakase!
Estou brincando! Pode parar de chorar, Doutora!
Fine, take it!
Pode pegar!
Take the Akutagawa Prize!
Pegue o Prêmio Akutagawa!
Why?!
Por quê?
Akutagawa Prize! Akutagawa Prize!
Prêmio Akutagawa!
This is my daily life...
Essa é a minha vida cotidiana.
Where am I?!
Onde estou?
Wake in the morning, teeth get a brushing
Você acorda de manhã, escova os dentes
Before you know it, it's ten at night
Antes que perceba, são dez da noite
Another day was full of laughter
Outro dia se foi, cheio de risadas
Another day filled with joy
Mais um dia cheio de alegria
Goofing with friends and acting so silly
Brincando com amigos, só de bobeira
Making a ruckus and then I see
Fazendo barulho e então eu vejo
A glimpse from you and then our eyes meet
Um vislumbre de você
Coincidence, or not?
Coincidência ou não?
I won't ever admit it's first love
Nunca vou admitir que é o primeiro amor
That's not something I would say
Isso não é algo que eu diria
Hey, I'll see you again tomorrow too.
Aí, vejo você de novo amanhã também
When I close my eyes I see
Quando eu fecho meus olhos eu vejo
My vision sparkling, filled with you
Minha visão brilhando, cheia de você
Wasn't it so much fun today?
Não foi muito divertido hoje?
Ah, I think I'm in love
Acho que estou apaixonada
I'm so happy I'm so happy
Estou tão feliz, estou tão feliz
Nice to meet you, awakening love
Prazer em conhecer, despertando amor
I'll see you again tomorrow too
Te vejo amanhã também
Good night
Boa noite
I'll see you again soon in my dreams
Eu te vejo de novo Em breve nos meus sonhos
Hello! I'm Nano's big toe.
Olá! Sou o dedão da Nano.
My capacity is one gigabyte.
Tenho um giga de capacidade.
Don't you wish I had more storage?
Você não quis me dar mais memória?
The next My Ordinary Life is Episode 2!
O próximo será o Episódio 02! Até lá!